Big hello guys. Hello. Uh so exciting
here. Sort of second iteration, new and
improved. Absolutely. And it's a
pleasure to it's a pleasure to introduce
Guy Pani, a friend of many years, but a
founder of Tesl and and obviously a
massive community figure uh for many
many years going back from security all
the way through to now AI but key is dev
tooling everything dev tooling
throughout that. So so guy what are you
going to be talking about today? Uh I
will talk about kind of the journey
we've been doing as a software ecosystem
on it. uh going from a super fun, super
magical, somewhat unreliable sort of AI
dev tools and vibe coding today to
evolving this as a craft. Uh yeah, very
interesting. It's the craft which I find
lovely because it's such a it's such a
uh so different so contrasting to to to
the vibe coding aspect. So GIO with that
I'll pass over to you. Uh thank you
Simon and I just want to echo Simon's
thank you for everyone for joining us
today. Hey, you know, it's really
exciting to run this as a second time,
as a recurring event, a community
resource of it. And I want to say an
extra thank you to all you amazing
people who are joining us a second time.
Hopefully that means we've done uh
something right in the previous one.
There are many hundreds of you. Uh and I
hope that you find this one even better,
even more compelling as we go through.
Uh so as Simon pointed out, I am Guy
Pojourney. I am the uh founder and CEO
here at Tessle. uh and I'm here to talk
about kind of the journey again what
we've been doing as but as we sort of
embrace AI into software
development. So, um, we've we've gone a
long way in a fairly short period of
time, right? If you hearken back not
long, maybe three years ago, the only AI
dev tool that had kind of any real
adoption was GitHub Copilot. And if you
fast forward to today, we have
thousands, potentially tens of thousands
of AI dev tools. In fact, so many of
them that we launched the AI native dev
landscape uh at the end of March. And we
we captured we tried to kind of help
curate a bunch of these tools out there
so people can find them and understand
them. We we curated about 150 tool in
less than two months. We got a bunch of
contributions on it. We're at nearly 300
now. Probably still have less than 10%
of the tools out there. And so with this
many tools, we now have some patterns to
learn from. We can see an evolution.
Maybe we can chart a trajectory. And so
I want to talk a little bit about this
journey that we've been on and uh kind
of finish off understanding what are the
limitations to kind of break through to
the next level and what can we do about
it. So to to plot that or to sort of uh
help us understand the journey, I'm
going to plot the plot it on this sort
of 2x two chart that I wrote about I
think it's September of last year. Uh
it's meant to help us understand AI
tools as a whole, not just dev. Uh and
it uses two axes. One is an axis of
trust. So how much do I need to trust
that a tool works to be able to for it
to be useful for me? So it goes from
attended to autonomous. And the second
is an axis of change. How much do I need
to change the way I work to be able to
embrace this tool. So let's look at a
couple of non-dev examples just to
understand it. Um for instance, when you
think about self-driving cars, you might
think that uh automatic parking or
staying in the lane, that is something
that doesn't change the way I work. I'm
driving. I'm in the same seat on it. and
it's highly attended. I I can and in
fact I'm expected to supervise and if
something goes wrong grab the wheel and
or not never take my hands off the wheel
uh and take over. While if you think for
instance about robo taxis and you know
Whimo and the likes uh they also don't
require a lot of change. I'm I'm pulling
up an app, I'm ordering a taxi, I walk
into a car or get into a car, get
driven, get off. Uh but the fact that
there's no driver there, but it's an
algorithm requires a lot of trust. I'm
entrusting it with with my life. Uh if
you think about and both of those
they're sort of journeys towards that
sort of top right destination of of the
sort of full self-driving car future.
And if you think about the change axis
you might uh think about text to video
for instance right it's a it's a new
form of creation that we have. We can
create images and videos with text. And
unlike the previous systems it's
entirely different. We're creating
videos with no cameras and things that
were were cheap uh or were expensive
before are now cheap. and vice versa.
And it really opens up a very disruptive
change of operations to be able to tap
the power of AI. And if you've been kind
of tracking
the ballerina capuccina Italian Tik Tok
and so uh I'm going to use this sort of
2 by two to chart the progress of AI dev
tools as they've gone through hoping it
is useful. and I will use kind of the
size of the dot uh to be able to express
a dot
level. So let's start with coding
assistance. Coding assistants are kind
of the uh the uh the OG uh tool and
still the most widely used AI dev tools.
They uh start from this notion of code
completion. Really the epitome of kind
of low change, low trust because we're
already used to IntelliSense to
completion of function names and such.
And so just the snippets of code that
get presented to us are are bigger, are
better, are smarter. Uh and we opt in to
those by hitting tab. And so fully
attended and uh very much very very
little change and no surprise they get
adopted substantially and still today
very clearly the most dominant most
actively used uh form of AI dev tool.
Next to that uh we've had the chach
craze and as a society we learned how to
use chacht for all sorts of things
including in coding asking for things
like hey create this function for me
maybe in python to use stripe to charge
for a transaction and chach will bring
in knowledge from uh what stripes API
looks like what is charging a
transaction knowledge about python and
create codes together and that saves a
ton of time of course when you use code
like that uh you don't understand you
what you've done and so if you encounter
an error you don't really know what to
do which led to another pattern of
behavior of taking that error and just
pasting it back into chat and say hey
what should I do now this problem
occurred and so this pattern led to a
very natural evolution of bringing that
chat into the IDE environment and being
able to just sort of ask those questions
in the IDE exchanging context and it
really introduced this notion of context
management so I can now sort of select a
piece of code instead of copy pasting it
and saying hey create unit for this
right or ask a question about it. These
are the core use cases for uh for sort
of coding assistance on it. And as we
started using them, we started
encountering some failures. And the
primary failures are really when it kind
of makes things up. You know, this
notion of hallucinations uh that really
start eroding the trust of I really want
to do this, but sometimes it's just
crazy. The most evident example of that
was really around APIs. Uh this is one
example from sort of a public pull
request that you know happens over the
time. You ask chachi PT uh I think this
is co-pilot for for help doing something
and it proposes this get spectral line
list function really nice really really
elegant uh and also entirely
non-existent like there is no function
call that it's a madeup API uh and that
can get really frustrating and again can
erode trust of if you got this wrong you
know what did you get wrong about
algorithms about you know functionality
in my code uh I want to share one of my
favorite examples here uh this is uh
April 24 so more than a year ago now
co-pilot in uh in the Tesla team created
this comment says to do Kevin this is a
hack to make Typescript happy which is
already kind of entertaining but it's
more entertaining when you realize uh
there is nobody named Kevin on the team
uh there was nobody named Kevin on the
team really unclear uh where that came
up uh where Copilot came up with it uh
and at this point I don't know that we
can hire a Kevin because since this
comment Kevin has become the ultimate
scapegoat uh for us whenever something
goes wrong so a lot of kind of a lot of
power and a lot of uh sort of questions
about trust. Let's plot these on the
map. Code completion clearly bottom left
big circle wide adoption. Uh really
little change, little trust required.
Chatbased codegen also little trust. You
choose to copy and paste something else.
However, a little bit of change. You
know, we're used to googling for a Kora
or Stack Overflow question, but the
interactive model, the breadth of it,
the specificity of it, it is it is a
change uh that people have kind of come
to embrace. So it's a pretty big circle
already. Coding assistants have
continued to improve. Uh they added many
things. A lot of them are doubling down
on the same concept. And so cursor
pioneered this notion of predictive
edits. You just sort of you modify one
part of the code uh and it would predict
you also want to change another part.
And so just hit tab and continue onwards
across lines and then over time across
files. When you introduce chat into this
mix, you you combine them again and you
ask for a modification instead of
changing code in one spot. It should
suggest a whole bunch of changes and
creates something that feels like a pull
request flow inside your browser. And
it's just you and the AI, so you can
move pretty quickly, but something we're
pretty familiar with and we accept it
with in theory supervision. We'll talk
about that more. So these bigger and
bigger edits translated uh or went
handinhand with growing awareness of the
code you are editing. And so we've seen
coding assistants introduce better and
better understanding of your codebase.
It went from no understanding of your
codebase. just a generic developer to
looking at the open tabs around it for
ad hoc context to allowing you to
control the context window and say hey
include these files to our current
expectations as you know really LLM
context windows have grown to really
have it just figure it out definitely
around the project that I'm on and many
tools today try to index entire massive
enterprise code bases and this sort of
deeper knowledge manifests in everything
the coding assistant does code
completions should get better and
represent your organization. Uh uh chat
queries allow us to start inquiring
question like asking questions about our
own big code base that previously maybe
we would have had to sort of search a
fair bit to find the answer to and then
when we create new assets, new projects,
new tests and such this institutional
knowledge basically kicks in to create
them. It did introduce uh an interesting
problem of sort of garbage in garbage
out. you know, inside your existing
codebase, there are patterns you want to
repeat and patterns you do not want to
repeat. Uh, and that's been a challenge
as we've learned kind of, you know, how
to tune it. Uh, that that actually the
industry is still dealing with.
So as we've been using more and more or
depending more and more on the systems
knowledge the trust problem also started
exploding and the evolution of that sort
of acute API mistake or hallucination
before uh evolved actually into a real
security concern uh called slop
squatting. Uh in this case this is a
research about it. Slop squatting was
actually sort of uh coined even
beforehand but in this research they
took a whole pile of prompts and tests
and they found out that a fifth of the
recommended packages were were
non-existent on it. That's higher than
what I've sort of anecdotally seen, but
it is it is a common occurrence. And
then they've also seen that 43% of the
time the same hallucinated packages were
suggested every time. And what that
means is an attacker can try a bunch of
prompts, see what the LLM hallucinates,
libraries that don't exist, and then
actually go off and create those
libraries uh and have them be malicious.
And so when the LLM goes on to
hallucinate because it's not based on
public knowledge, the use of a library,
that library will now get pulled in and
be malicious. And it's very hard for a
user to notice the fact that it's, you
know, a legitimately named but not
actually the popular package that they
were intending
for. So let's plot these enhancements.
You know, they're enhancements. They're
later. It makes sense. They're used
less. I would say multifile edits still
low on the change track. It is basically
a pull request in your browser but it is
higher in trust because you are
depending on the uh the system on the
sort of coding assistant to pick the
right files right when you think about
it if they consistently like don't pick
the right files they become useless to
you you'd stop using it altogether so
you have to trust they'll pick the right
files often codebase inquiries similarly
you're asking question about your
codebase you really need to trust that
that answer is correct but still for the
most part you can go vet it and I think
a little bit more change than chat we
didn't have such handy queries. Internal
docs often times fall out of date very
quickly and so it is new and we're
learning it but still for the most part
very much working in your workflow. No
big change required uh and uh generally
highly
attended which if we go continue to go
down that rabbit hole leads us to vibe
coding. So vibe coding uh is a term that
as many of you know has been coined by
Andre Karpathy and he in tweeted this
sort of pattern of behavior he spotted
in himself where he basically said you
know I asked cursor for stuff and I
don't really read the diffs anymore I
just kind of accept it when I get an
error message I just sort of throw it
copy past it back and forth and uh and
just sort of let it run and when that
happens the code grows beyond his usual
comprehension. So he acknowledges that
once he starts doing this, he's actually
no longer a good reviewer because he
doesn't actually understand the code
that is modified. Uh and he even
sometimes encounters dead ends where he
needs to either sort of stop or do
something funky to get over it. And he
says that's fine. It's not too bad for a
throwaway weekend project, but it's not
designed it's not meant for something
that you might do professionally, but it
is very very tempting.
uh vibe coding in this pattern of
behavior was made possible because of
cursors kind of accept all button uh at
the bottom that was really the leader
again now it's in many other tools uh
and uh it really kind of introduced an
easy way of sort of saying yeah this all
looks good with minimal or literally
zero uh vetting in fact cursor doubled
down on it and they created this notion
of the yolo mode I was kind of saddened
to see them rename this to auto run mode
it's a much more professional name but
like I liked yolo better uh and uh in
this case the accept all is basically
built in. You know, they they just go
off and uh and accept all the changes
automatically. Uh and in kind of
cursor's defense here, I don't know if
it's defense, but like the system does
acknowledge that it's taking on more
responsibility and when you put it in
yolo mode, it does run a few more tests
and you can give it some guidance about
what to do there. But still heavy heavy
heavy delegation to the LLM's decisions.
And uh it's worth noting that YOLO mode
I think it was pioneered by cursor but
it's not exclusive to it. Here's an
example of claude code which has this
auto accept edits uh option on it and
other tools kind of lean into this going
into agentic behavior we'll talk about
in a
sec. Um what could go wrong if you do
this? Uh everything everything can go
wrong. This is a zero guarantee
environment. There's no pretense really
of it just working or giving you any
assurances. This is again it's good for
it's not bad for a weekend project.
Clearly it's being used for more than
that but everything can go wrong. You
really have to trust it fairly
substantially. So plotting it on the
chart I would say first of all adoption
is still very low. I would actually say
that the adoption in professional
software development is higher than
maybe it should be because it's just oh
so tempting and we'll see if we pay the
kind of the price for that over time
with such software. Uh but it is still
nowhere near the sizes of the other
features we described. And uh I'd also
put it higher on the trust vector but
not so high. The reason for that is that
while you are delegating coding you're
still expected to vet the product. So
even even Karpathy as he uses it, he
does check if the product works. If you
contrast that to a self-driving car or
maybe like an intercom support agent
that gives answers automatically to its
customers, in that case, there is no
verification. And so there's still a
long way to go in terms of trust. You're
just not you're trusting its coding, but
you're not necessarily trusting its
correctness.
Now, of course, VIP coding continued
past this and there's a a new breed of
products, Lovable, Bolt, Vzero, Base 44,
there's a bunch of others that are what
I called prompt centric uh dev tools and
they give you access to the code, but
the products are really designed to say
you provide a prompt and then you see
the product and you it is an attended
product, but it's an attended product in
which you review the product, not the
code. And uh and you really are only
supposed to engage with the code when
there's a failure and you're trying to
do something very specific. And indeed
it drew many many users that are that
are not necessarily developers and many
use cases that are not professional
software development. These prompt
ccentric apps have mostly shine in
things that are disposable whether they
are prototypes or ad hoc systems. Uh
people you know someone might have an
idea they would create it in a
ridiculously short amount of time.
Amazing. I've done it many times now.
super fun. You go, you use it. You know,
maybe this is a kind of quiz quiz night
app for your friends. Maybe it's a
prototype of a new feature, right? Maybe
it's a a workshop tool that you're
using. And when you're done, you chuck
it in the bin. And these types of
disposable apps, you don't care as much
about their longevity, about their
correctness. They are small, so you can
vet and review all of their changes on
it. And so it works very well for those
use cases. However, when you try to grow
them past that, you start getting into
sort of experiences that the volatility
uh it's not so fun. Uh let's sort of see
this video is probably like a really
good way to demonstrate that. Make a
multiplayer flight simulator that's
going to make me rich.
See, this is all just hype. Engineers
are not going anywhere. You can't just
one-shot a flight simulator.
[Music]
It's magic. Engineers are going away
soon. Now make the planes
blue. No, no, no, no. Make it realistic
like before. More
realistic. More
realistic. This video, I've seen it, you
know, a thousand times. I don't know,
many times. Cracks me up every time. I
love the the pleading voice. I wonder if
LLM voice interpretation will
understand. I really mean it, you know,
when I'm pleading like this. Uh, so
these are are magical experiences. These
vibe coding environments like I I feel
that every time, no matter how many
times I do it and they're also so
unpredictable and so plotting them on
the map, I basically put them in a
different color. I'd say this is really
about toy dev adoption level. It is not
professional software development. They
have no notion of long-term ownership,
no notion of maintenance, no notion of
even like, you know, correctness. And at
the moment at least, they don't really
pretend to give you that. uh and so in
that sense it's just not professional
software development but I don't want to
diminish the level of adoption and value
they provide just for a different use
case so I plotted them in a slightly
different color in our path but they do
lead us to the obvious kind of
destination here which is agentic
development and this is really in a way
the attempt to bring this type of like
powerful behavior into the world of
professional development and as L&M's
got better and as uh capabilities like
MCP for instance made uh tool access for
agents
you know, more and more accessible just
like making agents more and more
powerful. Uh, it starts thinking of like
maybe this is more in the realm of
possible and many many solutions are
trying to build in that path. I see two
kind of primary big slots of of
autonomous agentic development
happening. The first one is agenticish
and this is cases in which you have some
narrow intelligence that can spot a
problem and fix the problem and then
propose that. So you see this maybe with
security issues for instance snake
finding a vulnerability fixing it and
proposing that to the user or code flesh
does that with performance. It's kind of
similar when you think about tests for
docs like something that is narrow
fairly independent but eventually the
acceptance of those changes into your
application that is still attended and
so it's you know there's some autonomy
but the workflow is still outside of
accepting it and running with it. So I'd
say it's agentic but it's it's sort of
not really autonomous.
Uh on the flip side you have these sort
of fully agentic uh development systems
and these really say hey I can do
something very broad. I can expand on
requirements. I can um uh I can uh
figure out the SDLC. I can figure out
where to deploy it and get it deployed
and fix issues on it. They're very
powerful. They've gotten a lot better
than when they were launched. Uh this
kind of category is is kind of probably
best exemplified with Devon. They were
the ones that sort of teed it up and
oftentimes they think about adv uh on it
with cognition labs. So definitely very
useful. It's still in that broad system.
There are many degrees of freedom and
it's been hard to accept it into
professional sort of software
development setting in enterprises.
However, many enterprises did start
using do start using it typically for
narrower use cases. So they might do
something similar to the previous
example or generate tests or generate
docs generate something that can still
be reviewed, can still be attended or
that has a smaller blast radius if it
got something wrong. Very very
promising. Still mostly a future. So as
we plot them on our chart, I would say
the narrow use cases, they show up over
here, uh they are uh they're still tiny
tiny compared to all the ones that we
talked about. It's still a nent use
case. Uh however, it's getting some uh
adoption on it. Typically, when you talk
about a Devon or such being used in
enterprises, my understanding is it's
mostly that use cases. The really true
broad use case, it's definitely in the
top right kind of a to future quadrant
is not really properly adopted today.
So I only kind of scratched the surface
in a bunch of tools here, but I think
these are like the primary paths of it.
I encourage you to check out the I
native dev landscape. See a whole bunch
of other amazing tools and we'll show
many of them in the tools uh track today
from uh product supporting product
management and requirements to to test
to documentation uh document generation
to devops to many others.
So what you might have noticed as I go
through it is is the key repetition is
this notion of a need for review and the
systems are getting better and better
and they do bigger and bigger things
typically correctly but they still can't
quite vouch for that and therefore they
require you to review and I don't think
reviews are here for the win. Uh and I
want to make the case about why that
is. First reviews get less attention and
as the article says attention is all you
need. uh really we we need that
attention as we when we read a piece of
code or content whatever it is we give
it less attention than when we've
written it. That's just a psychological
fact. And so things like a slight
performance issue like in the example
here or a security issue in which you
need to identify the absence of a
security control. It's always harder to
identify the absence of something. Uh
they you you just you it's easy to miss.
you know, they're far more likely to
miss. And there starts to come out, like
there's new data that starts to come out
uh that sort of supports this, it's all
still very nent, but also
psychologically it's it's quite obvious.
Uh and the more content you have to
review, the less attention you have to
uh spend on every one of those pieces.
And so imagine taking that accept all
and going not from like two files and,
you know, 31 lines of code changes to
2,000 files and 13,000 lines of code
changed. it it's really unfeasible like
you're effectively not reviewing in that
mode and so uh it really limits the
scale of change that a task that
requires a review would be able to do
maybe pulling on a thread that Carpathy
opened as well if if you you know you've
been using this for a few months and you
actually at this point haven't written
almost any of the code and you get a
piece of code to review are you even
able to review it um I I I think not and
I found it funny that actually cursor
when cornered actually agrees this is
a report from someone about a problem in
cursor where he complains that uh cursor
when it uh when the user tries to get
cursor to to continue writing code he
says I cannot generate code for you
looking at the end says you should
develop the logic yourself this ensures
you understand the system and can
maintain it properly uh this was a user
error he kind of clicked the wrong
button cut this message off it clear the
cursor will continue to write code for
you uh but I found it funny because it's
true uh if you didn't write the code you
can't really maintain And so reviewing
doesn't scale in in scope over time. It
just does not scale. And you know, it
really explodes when you start thinking
about maintenance. Can you really
imagine that your job as a developer is
to is to review every time there's a
dependency upgrade, every time there's
an API change, every time like basically
you have this sort of infinite list of
constant changes. Know it this this
would be terrible. It'll be humans as
the bottleneck and it would eliminate
all the productivity gains we get from
from accelerating coding by you know
trading re trading them for reviewing.
And the last point which is maybe the
most important is that reviewing is just
not fun right creation is fun coding is
fun reviewing is not and what we want AI
to do is take away the toil the nonf fun
part and if we become full-time
reviewers I don't think that's a
destination we want. I want to touch
this sort of notion of yolo, right? is
like this is uh hey why don't we just
sort of skip the reviews it's fine they
will typically get it right this is hard
when you think about software as it
grows you know the multiplications of
probabilities like how many times you
deployed to the software uh multiplied
by how many pieces of software are there
and changes that have occurred even a
01% likelihood of change really can
explode and the problem is that AI is
not accountable for those mistakes
humans are right corporations are and so
if you wanted to just kind of yolo and
trust it and you know what the heck. The
problem is you're going to be held
accountable to it and you have to think
about whether your trust in that uh is
high enough that you're willing to
accept the outcomes. And I think
society-wise we'll also get to the point
where where we're asked at what point
does trusting AI become negligent?
Right? If a self-driving car runs over a
person and the the the corporation
behind it says, "Well, we delegated the
decision to the AI and we thought it was
good and it works, you know, 99.99% of
the time." At what point does someone
say, "Well, that's not okay. You needed
to have some safety controls and
delegating to AI is deemed a negligent
action. What about a software bug that
took down a critical system?" I don't
know what the thresholds are, but
accountability is a real topic when we
think about trust.
So I think as an ecosystem it's worth
saying that we're we're at a point in
which we're ready for a commitment. You
know we need uh uh AI development tools
that are able to make some commitments
about what it is that they create
despite they themselves being stocastic
entities and let's maybe think a little
bit about intelligence and
collaboration. So societies are built on
trust right we have different entities
different people. We make commitments to
one another. We deliver on those
commitments and therefore we build trust
right? You go to the ger, they commit
the food is fresh. They uh you go to,
you know, you you get some currency on
foreign exchange and they commit that
the currency will hold. Granted, a bit
dubious these days on it, but that's the
intent of trust there, right? That the
plane is safe. And we use these these
commitments as they get delivered on
again and again and again. They build
trust that they will happen again and we
we we penalize those who do not. And
similarly, organizations are built on
trust, right? different developers agree
on division of responsibilities and API
and different dev teams do that or you
know dev and the business side of it
will talk about you know fulfilling
business needs on it and of course
importantly users engage with a
corporation and they put their trust on
it because the corporation is committed
to keeping your data safe to keeping the
airplanes safe to keeping the prices
low and so the way out I think of this
sort of limit to be able to break
through that sort of ceiling here of
attendance to autonomous we need a
mechanism as a as a as a community uh
that allows us to go from human reviews
to something that is more of a
structured commitment and I'd like to
give a couple of lenses on this for us
to consider. I don't yet have a solution
on it. Frankly, we're working on some of
this in Tessle. Uh but I think it's
broader than that and just to think
directionally what is it that we should
have in our systems. I think there are
two types of commitments. The first type
is a product commitment. This is
committing to some this is a commitment
around what is being built. And so there
would always be a checkout button. You
would always have a way to export your
data. you would uh always uh be able to
use the standard algorithm to uh I don't
know like convert some numbers some
mathematical numbers and you want to
capture those requirements in a spec and
you want to be able to to uh find a way
to to hard commit to them with some
tests or verifications. And we think
that that's at the core of being able to
scale software because you have
different pieces of software and for
them to depend on one another they have
to commit uh to functionality to
interfaces to be able to to join
together. And so this is about what is
built. The second type of commitment is
around how it is built. We want to say I
I will commit to it always uh being
tested for security issues. I will
commit to uh this path of long-term
maintenance of it to the update
mechanism to auditability and this is
key in general for building trust with
users. It's true for regulatory and and
kind of compliance needs of it and over
time it is true for uh it is it is
necessary uh once again for
collaborations because commitment about
you know uh functionality without
commitment about quality are a bit of a
dead
end. A slightly different lens is
commitment boundaries. And so there are
commitments between a human developer
and the AI. This is the primary thing we
talked about here. I'm building a
system. How do I get the AI to work to
my
commitments? That in turn allows the
development team to commit to things to
the organization. We'll be on time, on
budget. We will be compliant with so and
so. And then the organization can go off
and commit to the user. And these
commitment boundaries don't just need to
exist. We also need to think about how
do we communicate them. What is the
mechanism of of conveying what are you
committing to and what are you
not? And to to close off I want to talk
about the two paths we can take as an
ecosystem. So I see sort of two paths of
evolution. One is the sort of big brain
path. Uh it's a path in which there's
sort of a big system. It sucks up all
the information and it just sort of gets
it more and more and more correctly. And
then it does use tools and systems
around it, but they're extensions.
They're like a Chrome extension or a
Slack app or they're just helpers. All
the power is concentrated in in these
sort of one, two, three big platforms.
The platform you use, you get better and
better. And I I think that's a bit of a
sad path because it doesn't leave room
for these different innovators to to to
grow and to thrive. Uh the other path is
one of of an ecosystem of collaborators
that commit to one another on interfaces
on functionality on quality and in that
case different ones different uh uh tool
providers different systems can be extra
good at a specific domain whether it's
through data or experience or whatever
it may be whether it's test generation
or doc versus doc generation versus code
generation whether it is specific stacks
or business functionality they can build
competence and as consumer consumers of
them. We can choose how we want to mix
and match
them. At Tesla, we believe in an open
ecosystem and we think that requires a
means of creating software with the
magic of AI that enables commitment and
we are driving towards this path. And my
question to you is, are you ready to
commit to
it? That's it for me. Thank you.
Awesome. A big thank you to uh to GIO
and um yeah very interesting in uh in in
I guess the path that we've come on and
what's very interesting is the path
that's still to go on right guy. Uh
yeah. Yeah, absolutely. And you know, we
we're we're working on sort of uh
building the pieces, but I think many of
these are meta pieces. Like just like a
lot of these tools, they have strengths
and weaknesses. We need to think about
how do we how kind of bring forward this
balance, the slider between predictable,
committed software and software that is
adaptable and kind of leans on the
intelligence of uh of AI.